

Ph.D in Computer Vision and Deep Learning

□+39 334 8756245 | ■roberto.bigazzi.1995@gmail.com | 🏕 bigazzon.github.io | 🖸 bigazzon | 🛅 roberto-bigazzi

Summary.

I'm a Post-Doc Researcher at the University of Modena and Reggio Emilia, in the AlmageLab research laboratory supervised by the Professor Rita Cucchiara. The main topics of my research are Computer Vision and Deep Learning, in particular on robotic visual navigation.

I pursued my Ph.D. at AlmageLab research laboratory after completing my Master's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering at the Polytechnic University of Milan, with the Professor Marco Gribaudo. During my Ph.D. program, I spent a period as visiting student researcher at Stanford University in the Autonomous Systems Lab (ASL) directed by the Professor Marco Pavone.

Knowledge and Technical Skills

Domains Visual Navigation, Multimodal Learning, Natural Language Processing, Reinforcement Learning, Deep Learning

Programming Python, Java, Javascript, C++, C#, C, MATLAB, SQL, Microcontroller Programming (Arduino)

Frameworks and Other PyTorch, OpenCV, Numpy, Pandas, TFX, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, ROS, Git, Android Programming, MySQL

Languages Italian (Mothertongue), English (Proficient *TOEIC (C1), FCE (B2)*)

Education

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Ital

POST-DOC RESEARCHER: COMPUTER VISION AND DEEP LEARNING

Mar. 2023 - present

· Research on Visual Navigation and Multimodal Learning

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY IN INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGIES: COMPUTER VISION AND DEEP LEARNING

Nov. 2019 - Mar. 2023

• Multimedia Data Learning at Almagelab under the supervision of Prof. Rita Cucchiara

Stanford University Stanford, California, United S

VISITING STUDENT RESEARCHER May 2022 - Aug. 2022

• Research on Visual Navigation at Autonomous Systems Lab (ASL) under the supervision of Prof. Marco Pavone

Polytechnic University of Milan

Milan, Italy

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2017 - Oct. 2019

• Final Grade: 108/110. Thesis with Prof. Marco Gribaudo: "Enhancing Spatial Navigation in Robot-Assisted Surgery: a case study"

Technische Universität Wien

Vienna, Austria

Erasmus+ Exchange Semester Oct. 2018 - Feb. 2019

Polytechnic University of Milan

Milan, Ital

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Sep. 2017

• Final Grade: 99/110

Pubblications

2023 International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

Embodied Agents for Efficient Exploration and Smart Scene Description

Roberto Bigazzi, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Marcella Cornia, Rita Cucchiara

2022 ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION LETTERS (RA-L) + INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION (ICRA)

Focus on Impact: Indoor Exploration with Intrinsic Motivation

Roberto Bigazzi, Federico Landi, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Marcella Cornia, Rita Cucchiara

2022 26TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON PATTERN RECOGNITION (ICPR)

Spot the Difference: A Novel Task for Embodied Agents in Changing Environments

Federico Landi, Roberto Bigazzi, Marcella Cornia, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

2023 22ST INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON IMAGE ANALYSIS AND PROCESSING (ICIAP)

Towards Explainable Embodied Navigation and Recounting

Samuele Poppi, Roberto Bigazzi, Niyati Rawal, Marcella Cornia, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

2021 21ST INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON IMAGE ANALYSIS AND PROCESSING (ICIAP)

Embodied Navigation at the Art Gallery

Roberto Bigazzi, Federico Landi, Silvia Cascianelli, Marcella Cornia, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

2021 19TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER ANALYSIS OF IMAGES AND PATTERNS (CAIP)

Out of the Box: Embodied Navigation in the Real World

Roberto Bigazzi, Federico Landi, Marcella Cornia, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

2020 25TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON PATTERN RECOGNITION (ICPR) (ORAL PRESENTATION)

Explore and Explain: Self-supervised Navigation and Recounting

Roberto Bigazzi, Federico Landi, Marcella Cornia, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

UNDER REVIEW

Indoor Semantic Region Mapping: Language-grounded Visual Recognition for Embodied Navigation

Roberto Bigazzi, Shreyas Kousik, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara, Marco Pavone

UNDER REVIEW

AIGeN: An Adversarial Approach for Instruction Generation in Vision-and-Language Navigation

Niyati Rawal, Roberto Bigazzi, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

UNDER REVIEW

UNMuTe: Unifying Navigation and Multimodal Dialogue-like Text Generation

Niyati Rawal, Roberto Bigazzi, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

Experience _____

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

RESEARCH FELLOW

Nov. 2019 - present

Research during Doctorate at AlmageLab.

PrometeiaBologna, ItalyLECTURERNov. 2021

LEGIONER

Python and Machine Learning course for Banco BPM

IFOA Modena / Bologna Modena / Bologna, Italy

 LECTURER
 Jan. 2021 - Apr. 2021

"Deep Learning, Artificial Intelligence e Neurolinguistic Processing" and "Data Analysis and Data Visualization" courses.

Cyber-Physical Systems Group - Technische Universität Wien

Vienna. Austria

PROJECT DEVELOPER

Oct. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Project performed on the creation of a vertical farming system during the course of Internet of Things of the Professor Ezio Bartocci at TU Wien.

Teaching Activities _____

- 2020-23 **Teaching Assistant**, Computer Architectures
- 2021-22 **Lecturer and Project Tutor**, Al for Automotive
- 2020-21 **Project Tutor**, Neural Network Computing, Al and Machine Learning for Automotive
- 2019-20 **Project Tutor**, Computer Vision and Cognitive Systems

Program Committees _____

Peer Reviewer, IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)

Peer Reviewer, IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters (GRSL)

Peer Reviewer, IEEE Pattern Recognition Letters (PRL)

Peer Reviewer, Transactions on Multimedia Computing Communications and Applications (TOMM)

Peer Reviewer, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)

Peer Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

Peer Reviewer, IAPR International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR)

Peer Reviewer, ACM International Conference on Multimedia

According to law 679/2016 of the Regulation of the European Parliament of 27th April 2016, I hereby express my consent to process and use my data provided in this document and application for recruiting purposes.